#### Krittika Mahattanakul

Business Development Executive kmahattan@hotmail.com +668 1731 7743

## **Curriculum Vitae**

# **Career Highlights**

Extensive managerial experience from Corporate Vision & Mission, Strategy, Finance and Control, Sales, Marketing and Communication, People Management, Customer Relationship Management, New Business Development to Business operation at multinational organization in Asia Pacific, China, South America and global levels.

Known as a high-energy professional with demonstrated success & ability to serve in a leadership capacity, and effectively communicate with individuals at all levels of the organization up to Board of Director.

Manage the country subsidiaries with the responsibility of its Profit & Loss, Sales & Marketing, Services Delivery, Organization development and Customer Relationship Management.

Strong background and experience in strategizing and implementing short and long term business planning, organization development and performance management, marketing & communication and Go-to-market activities include managing Regional/Local business partners on new opportunities/countries.

Very good knowledge on set-up/restructuring the organization for better efficiency & performance, and excellent management skills in identifying business challenge, designing the business plans, initiating the changes in the company and managing/implementing a new process to drive the organization toward the targets.

## IBM Thailand Co, Ltd. (December 2014 – Present)

#### **Business Development Executive**

Drive and own the complex deals across the industries/sectors in Thailand i.e. from identifying, validating, and qualifying until contract signed.

#### Intouch Holdings Public Company Limited (September 2013 – June 2014)

#### **Executive Vice President, New Business**

Explore new business opportunities for the group in Telecom, IT, Media and Digital Content. Ensure that new investment delivers sustainable growth and long term value to shareholders. Focus were Digital Content, Venture Capital, Digital TV, Cloud Computing and Fixed Broadband.

#### Nokia Siemens Networks (April 2007 – June 2013)

#### Head of Asia North, Asia Pacific, May 2009 – June 2013

- Provide leadership, strategic direction to Sub region/country subsidiaries. Responsible for overall business plannings, P&L and business operations. And also managing organization development, sales & marketing, services delivery, business excellence, quality in Asia North Sub region i.e. Bangladesh, Cambodia, Laos, Myanmar, South Korea (until 2011), Thailand and Vietnam.

#### Head of Services Sales, Latin America, April 2007 – April 2009

- Provide strategic direction, overall business planning including strategy and objectives for Services sales in Latin America with high focus in Argentina, Brazil, Chile, Colombia, Ecuador, Mexico, Peru, and Venezuela.

## Nokia Networks (January 1995 – March 2007)

## Director, South Sub Area CMCC CBT, China, May 2006 - March 2007

- Overall business planning, sales and operations for South China under China Mobile customer team e.g. together 10 provinces.

## Services Sales Director, Asia Pacific, Oct 2003 - Apr 2006

- Provide strategic direction, overall business planning including strategy and objectives for Services sales planning in Asia Pacific

## Country Manager of Thailand, Services, Jan 2004 – Dec 2004

- Provide direction, people management, responsible for projects execution with team of 60+ employees

## General Manager, Scandinavia, Hutchison CBT, Jul 2002 – Sep 2003

- Provide team direction, business planning and execution

# General Manager - AIS, Thailand, Singtel CBT, Jan 1999 – Jun 2002

- Provide team direction, business planning and execution

#### Senior Account Manager - DPC, Thailand, Nov 1996 - Dec 1998

- Responsible for sales and customer relationship

# Account Manager - State Enterprise i.e. TOT, CAT, Thailand, Jan 1995 - Oct 1996

- Responsible for sales and customer relationship

# Big Communications Co., Ltd. (1993 to 1994)

**Marketing & Sales Division Manager** 

- Managing sales and marketing for GPT and Hitachi PBX in Thailand

# **Busicom Engineering Co., Ltd. (1987 to 1993)**

Various positions e.g. Marketing Manager, Product Manager, Technical Services Manager, Chief Engineer

#### **Education and professional training**

Director Certification Program (DCP188) – IOD 2014

Duke Corporate Education London – NSN Executive Leader - 2010

NSN Strategic Leadership – 2010

Nokia Solution Selling – 2004

Nokia Navigating Through Stormy Water - 2003

London Business School – Operator Business Strategy – 2002

Nokia Networker – 1999

Master of Business Administration (EMBA), SASIN (Joint program between Kellogg, Wharton and Chulalongkorn University in Thailand)

Bachelor of Engineering (B.Eng control), King Mongkut Institute of Technology